Guide to the Richard Pollay Acme Advertising Collection, 1850s-2006 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Series 16: Posters, Magazine and Newspaper Advertisements, 1898-2004 and undated
  - 100-16-060. Acme Harvesting Machine Company, undated (Box 41)
    Acme machines are ll the name means. Black-and-white images and text. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-16-061. Acme Cycle Company, undated (Box 41)
    We employ thousands of responsible persons of both sexes to distribute our advertising in part payment for a HIGH GRADE Acme Bicycle... Black-and-white images and text. Yellowing. Circa late 1880s-1900s. Good condition.
  - 100-16-062. Acme Harvester Company, undated (Box 41)
    Hodges New Steel Chain Drive Header. Black-and-white images and text. Yellowing. Circa late 1880s-1900s. Good condition.
  - 100-16-063. Acme Gloves, undated (Box 42)
    Beautiful to their finger tips. Red and Black imagery and text. Yellowing. Minor creases. Good condition.
  - 100-16-064. Garderobedesign, undated (Box 42)
    Mangler De skabsplads. Black-and-white image and text. Text in Danish. Taken from newspaper. Good condition.
  - 100-16-065. Acme Mobile Homes Inc., undated (Box 42)
    New, Used, Repos. Newspaper advertisement. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-066. Garderobedesign, undated (Box 42)
    Mangler De skabsplads. Black-and-white image and text. Text in Danish. Taken from newspaper. Good condition..
  - 100-16-067. Smith Corona Corp, undated (Box 42)
    What this did for cars, we've done for typewriters and word processors. Black-and-white image of car muffler and text against pale yellow background. Torn out of magazine. Good condition..
  - 100-16-068. Acme White Lead and Color Works, 1923 (Box 42)
    Let the Acme Quality Agent Help You. Copy of original. Black-and-white image and text. Folded. Good condition..
  - 100-16-069. Acme White Lead and Color Works, 1919 (Box 42)
    Acme Quality Paints and Finishes. Copy of original. Black-and-white image and text. Folded. Good condition..
  - 100-16-070. Acme White Lead and Color Works, 1923 (Box 42)
    Make Home Beautiful...And Protect Home Beauty...With Acme Quality. Copy of original. Black-and-white image and text. Folded. Good condition..
  - 100-16-071. Acme White Lead and Color Works, 1923 (Box 42)
    10,000 Feet Tramp Through Your House. Copy of original. Black-and-white image and text. Folded. Good condition..
  - 100-16-072. Acme White Lead and Color Works, 1925 (Box 42)
    Up and Down Main Street. Copy of original. Black-and-white image and text. Folded. Good condition..
  - 100-16-073. Acme White Lead and Color Works, undated (Box 42)
    I'd have thought it a new rig if I hadn't seen you painting it. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-074. Acme White Lead and Color Works, 1948 (Box 42)
    Newest Idea in Paint! Color text and images. Good condition.
  - 100-16-075. Acme White Lead and Color Works, 1948 (Box 42)
    Have the best looking house in town! Use Acme House Paint! Color text and images. Good condition.
  - 100-16-076. Acme White Lead and Color Works, 1948 (Box 42)
    Give your house that NEW paint look with Acme House Paint. Color text and images. Good condition.
  - 100-16-077. Acme Electric Heater Company. Electric iron, 1913 (Box 42)
    The Acme Armored Electric Sad Iron. Black-and-white text and images. Good condition. Published: Good Housekeeping Magazine April 1913.
  - 100-16-078. Missouri Lamp and Mfg. Company. Fire extinguisher, 1909 (Box 42)
    Fire! Fire! Fire! The Cry May Cause Alarm But with the protection of an Acme Fire extinguisher the damage is avoided where usually 100 gallons of water are applied. Black-and-white text and images. Fragile condition.
  - 100-16-079. Sears Roebuck and Company. Acme Grand Cast Iron Range, undated (Box 42)
    Acme Grand Six-hole Cast Iron Range. Copy of page from Sears Roebuck catalog. Creased and folded. Poor condition.
  - 100-16-080. Mendleson Corporation. Acme Lime, undated (Box 42)
    Your barn may endanger your home...this danger can be utterly wiped out by the use of Acme Chlorinated Lime. Black-and-white image and text. Yellowing. Fragile condition.
  - 100-16-081. Acme Harvesting Machine Company, 1916 (Box 42)
    Acme Machines are all the name means. Black-and-white image and text. Yellowing. Fragile condition. Taken from: The Iowa Homestead April 6 1916.
  - 100-16-082. Acme Water Storage and Construction Company, 1911 (Box 42)
    For public water supplies, country residences, institutions, residences. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition. Printed in Country Life in America, November 1911.
  - 100-16-083. Acme Spring Beds Company, undated (Box 42)
    Acme Hygienic Couches Made to Last. Black-and-white image and text. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-16-084. Acme Sales Company. Fireworks, undated (Box 42)
    Get 'em now for July Fourth! Black-and-white image and text. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-16-085. Acme Lite Manufacturing Company, 1949 (Box 42)
    A New Lightning Package. Advertises a portrait light for photographers. Black-and-white image and text. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-16-086. Acme Manufacturing Company. Safety Truck and Wagon Dump, undated (Box 42)
    The Acme Safety Truck and Wagon Dump will be a Trade Maker for you Just what the name signifies--The Acme of Perfection for you. Black-and-white image and text. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-16-087. Acme Motor Car Company, 1910? (Box 42)
    The Acme Justifies its Name. Special Sextuplet. 6 cylinder. 50 H. P. $4.75. Black-and-white image and text. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-16-088. Acme Motor Car Company, 1910 (Box 42)
    We beg to announce...the 1911 Model...$2200-$2500. Black-and-white image and text. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-16-089. Acme Motor Car Company, 1900 (Box 42)
    The Acme Quad. A touring car that withstands the hardest kind of touring... Black-and-white image and text. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-16-090. Acme Washing Machine Company, 1907 (Box 42)
    Who does your washing? Do you do it your self...Does a washer woman do it?...Do you send it to a laundry? The Improved Acme Washer... Black-and-white image and text. Yellowing. Dark stain top right. Torn from magazine. Good condition.
  - 100-16-091. Acme Washing Machine Company, 1907 (Box 42)
    The improved Acme Washer has more convenient attachments and does more and better work than any other washer at the same or even higher price. Black-and-white image and text. Yellowing. Good condition. Printed in Ladies Home Journal March 1907.
  - 100-16-092. Nash and Brother. Acme Pulverizing Harrow and Clod Crusher, 1882 (Box 42)
    The Acme cuts over the entire surface of the ground and leaves no ridges. Black-and-white image and text. Newsprint. Yellowing. Fragile condition. Printed in Tribune farmer January 28 1882. Dimensions refer to size of advertisement on page. Context has been maintained by leaving the advertisement in its original format. See: Duane Nash for other earlier advertising related to product.
  - 100-16-093. Acme Chevrolet Company Inc., undated (Box 42)
    Take the heat of all summer. Color image and text. Folded. Signs of wear. Good condition.
  - 100-16-094. Acme MFG Company. Canoe, undated (Box 42)
    Untold pleasures await the owner of an Acme. Copy of original. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-095. Acme Oil and Development Company, undated (Box 42)
    Your chance...Stock advances...Be wise--Buy Acme Oil at 20c a share. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition. Printed in Pacific Monthly Advertising Section.
  - 100-16-096. Acme Pattern and Tool Inc., 1943 (Box 42)
    Acme for Action. Quick action on attack brings many glorious victories to our gallant Navy. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition. Printed in Aero Digest September 1943.
  - 100-16-097. Acme Card System Company. Visible Card System, 1920s (Box 42)
    When the unusual happens... Black-and-white image and text. Advertises record keeping system. Starting to yellow. Good condition.
  - 100-16-098. Acme Card System Company. Visible Card System, 1923 (Box 42)
    The $100,000 worth of business we found hiding in our card files. Black-and-white image and text. Advertises record keeping system. Starting to yellow. Good condition. Printed in National Geographic, November 1923.
  - 100-16-099. Acme Card System Company. Visible Card System, 1930 (Box 42)
    Expense? No! They're an investment. Earning profits hourly! Black-and-white image and text. Advertises record keeping system. Starting to yellow. Good condition. Printed in Time Magazine, April 21, 1923.
  - 100-16-100. Acme Cycle Company, 1903 (Box 42)
    Dealers wanted to act as agents for ACME BICYCLES. Black-and-white image and text. Framed--glued on to red mat board. Advertisement is starting to yellow. Good condition.
  - 100-16-101. Acme Aluminum Ltd., 1978 (Box 42)
    Factory-Direct-To-You. Black-and-white image and text. Newsprint. Yellowing. Good condition. Printed in Vancouver Sun, February 3, 1978.
  - 100-16-102. Acme Stove, 1978 (Box 42)
    For Modern Economical Thermostatic Slow-Burn Wood Heat. Newsprint. Yellowing. Good condition. Printed in Vancouver Sun, February 3, 1978.
  - 100-16-103. Acme Hardware Company Inc., undated (Box 42)
    World's Largest Selection of Hand Carved Doors and Decorators Hardware. Newsprint. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-16-104. National Phonographic Company. Edison Phonograph, undated (Box 11)
    The Acme of realism. The Edison Phonograph. Color copy of the original. Light weight cardboard. Evidence of paper stuck with glue on reverse. Good condition.
  - 100-16-105. Acme Boot Company, 1951 (Box 11)
    Hopalong Cassidy...Here's your pal...Hopalong Cassidy...And his brand new cowboy boots! Color image and text. Good condition. Printed in Saturday Evening Post March 15,1951.
  - 100-16-106. Acme Brief Case Company, 1949 (Box 11)
    Ride our ranges with republic star Roy Rogers school bags. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-107. Acme Visible Records Inc., 1943 (Box 11)
    Save Time. For Victory make each minute count...Only you know whether you are patriotic...the difference between full use of your working time with wholehearted effort or just getting by tells the story. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-108. Acme Gloves, 1948 (Box 11)
    Gloves by Acme. Beautiful to their fingertips. Color image and text. Starting to yellow. Good condition. Printed Canadian Home Journal November 1948.
  - 100-16-109. Acme Wire Company, 1925 (Box 11)
    Power and Light for the Farm. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition. Printed in Scientific American.
  - 100-16-110. Acme White Lead and Color Works, 1921 (Box 11)
    The Immaculate gloss of white enameled woodwork. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-111. Acme White Lead and Color Works, 1948 (Box 11)
    Have the best looking house in town! Color text and image. Good condition.
  - 100-16-112. Acme White Lead and Color Works, 1923 (Box 11)
    The storm that lasted 625 days! Black-and-white image and text. Paper is highly acidic and very yellow. Small tears. Fragile condition. Printed in The Country Gentlemen, April 14, 1923.
  - 100-16-113. Acme Steel Company, 1953 (Box 11)
    Acme Steel Strapping Insures SA--Safe Arrival. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition. Printed in Saturday Night Post March 28, 1953.
  - 100-16-114. Acme Visible Records Inc., 1949 (Box 11)
    Forecast or Guess? Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-115. Acme Visible Records Inc., undated (Box 11)
    At a glance. Control...By Management assures Efficiency. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-116. Acme Visible Records Inc., 1947 (Box 11)
    Co-ordinated Operation Through Recorded Facts. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-117. Acme Visible Records Inc., 1949 (Box 11)
    When you get them together, the various instruments in an orchestra produce harmonious tunes. In the same way facts obtained from your records permit for fast decisions and better control of your business. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-118. Acme Visible Records Inc., 1943 (Box 11)
    Vision records systems make an unbeatable hand for effective management control. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-119. Acme Visible Records Inc., 1940s (Box 11)
    There is an ACME Visible Record System for every record requirement...and every one is a real Time saver... Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-120. Acme Visible Records Inc., undated (Box 11)
    It took me fully an hour. Time is to valuable to be used in search for facts... Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-121. Acme Visible Records Inc., 1931 (Box 11)
    Sales Manager or Cheer Leader?--Profit Builders of the Modern Industry. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition. Printed in time Magazine May 4, 1931.
  - 100-16-122. Acme Visible Records Inc., 1944 (Box 11)
    100% Visibility. Vision Systems spotlight the record facts for analysis and action! Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-123. Acme White Lead and Color Works, 1925 (Box 11)
    Up and Down Main St. Advertisement provides testimonials of happy customers--majority are women. Color text and image. Good condition.
  - 100-16-124. Acme White Lead and Color Works, 1940s (Box 11)
    Glorious new Acme Paints. Colors harmonizes with Ken-Tone walls. Color text and image. Good condition.
  - 100-16-125. Acme Coppersmithing Company, Inc., undated (Box 11)
    Advertises products and facilities. Black-and-white image and text. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-16-126. Acme Boot Company, 1954 (Box 11)
    Play is more fun in cowboy boots! Color text and image. Good condition.
  - 100-16-127. Acme Boot Company, 1954 (Box 11)
    All America is getting into Cowboy boots. Color text and image. Good condition.
  - 100-16-128. Acme Boot Company, 1956 (Box 11)
    Make this an ACME Cowboy boot Christmas. Color text and image. Good condition.
  - 100-16-129. Chevrolet Motor Company, 1934 (Box 11)
    Every truck owner knows every valve-in-head six costs less to run. Image is of an Acme truck being loaded with freight. Black, white and green text and imagery. Good condition.
  - 100-16-130. Acme Markets, Inc., 1962 (Box 11)
    Have turkey will gobble. Image of boy eating turkey leg is by Norman Rockwell. Color text and image. Good condition.
  - 100-16-131. Acme Markets, Inc., undated (Box 11)
    Acme Coffee Reward! Save 66% on Imported English and Bone China Cup and Saucer Set. Color text and image. Good condition.
  - 100-16-132. Acme Automotive Finishes, 1950 (Box 11)
    Yours for a profitable business lifetime. The Acme way. Makes Painting Pay. Color text and image. Good condition.
  - 100-16-133. Acme Industries Inc., 1954 (Box 11)
    Wherever temperature poses a [problem in industry, in commerce, at home, you'll find ACME air conditioning and refrigeration facilities. Black-and-white image and text. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-16-134. Acme Boot Company, 1952 (Box 11)
    Acme Cowboy Boots. Worlds largest makers of cowboy boots. Color image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-135. Acme Boot Company, 1948 (Box 11)
    Get into step with fun!-- For all the family. Color image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-136. Philco Storage Battery Company, 1926 (Box 11)
    ...And then he got his Philco! Tremendous surplus power...oversize capacity... Black and white image and text. Starting to yellow. Good condition.
  - 100-16-137. Acme Wire Company, 1921 (Box 11)
    He sells Magnet Wire on a totally new basis... Black and white image and text. Small tears. Good condition. Printed in Literary Digest.. April 2, 1921.
  - 100-16-138. Acme Wire Company, 1920s (Box 11)
    Inside your electric cleaner. Nearly a million new vacuum cleaners start work in American homes this year... Black and white image and text. Good condition. Printed in the American Magazine.
  - 100-16-139. Acme Wire Company, 1921 (Box 11)
    Some Users of Acme Magnet Wire...Acme Wire. It goes in the Space. Black and white image and text. Good condition. Printed in Literary Digest. February 5, 1921.
  - 100-16-140. Acme Wire Company, 1920s (Box 11)
    Acme Wire Products in Delco Systems. Black and white image and text. Starting to yellow. Good condition. Printed in the American Magazine.
  - 100-16-141. Acme Card System Company, 1917 (Box 11)
    5240 Items are before her eyes. Acme Sight Card System... Black and white image and text. Starting to yellow. Good condition.
  - 100-16-142. Acme Visible Records Inc., 1940s (Box 11)
    Visualize for Victory with Vision. Black and white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-143. Acme Industries Inc., 1967 (Box 11)
    How Many of Fortunes Top 500 US Corps. Use Acme Comfort and Process Cooling Equipment. Red, white and black images and text. Yellowing at edges. Good condition. Printed in Fortune Magazine June 15, 1967.
  - 100-16-144. Acme Motor Car, 1905 (Box 42)
    At The Top. Acme Details Show Character. Black-and-white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-145. Duane H. Nash Inc., 1914 (Box 42)
    Acme Foot Lift Weeder. --A riding orchard cultivator and mulcher... Black-and-white image and text. Yellowing. Good condition.
  - 100-16-146. Acme-Litho Inc., undated (Box 11)
    Depth--Dexterity--Tone. Color orchestration by Acme-Litho--keeping in tune with the times. Color text and image. Photo-lithography. Good condition.
  - 100-16-147. Acme-Litho Inc., undated (Box 11)
    Warmth--Feeling--Mellowness. Color orchestration by Acme-Litho--keeping in tune with the times. Color text and image. Photo-lithography. Good condition.
  - 100-16-148. Acme Slide Rule Company, undated (Box 11)
    Poster of dragon holding school satchel labeled Acme Slide Rule Company. Mock-up of advertising poster? Color. Good condition.
  - 100-16-149. Acme-Litho Inc., undated (Box 11)
    Puissance -Rythme--Vie. Chez Acme-Litho--on connait la musique. Color text and image. Photo-lithography. Good condition.
  - 100-16-150. Acme Aluminum Ltd., undated (Box 42)
    Black and white image and text. Newsprint. Good condition.
  - 100-16-151. Acme Bar-B-Q, undated (Box 42)
    Blues B-B-Q. Black and white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-152. Acme Photo Finishing, undated (Box 42)
    We're 10 years old this month... Newsprint. Black and white image and text. Small tear top left. Roughly cut out of original paper. Good condition.
  - 100-16-153. Acme Superstore, 1991 (Box 42)
    Newspaper spread advertising Acme Superstore products. Folded in quarters. Yellowing. Fair condition.
  - 100-16-154. Acme Apparatus Company, undated (Box 42)
    Have the fun of building your own (radio) with Acme parts. Photocopy of original advertisement. Folded. Good condition.
  - 100-16-155. Acme Washing Machine Company, 1907 (Box 48B)
    Who does your washing? Do it your self? Does a washer woman do it? Do you send it to a laundry? Black and white image and text. Young girl smiling as she easily uses an Acme Washer. Excellent Condition. Published by The Ladies Home Journal 1907.
  - 100-16-156. Acme Boot Company. Sign, undated (Box 11)
    One yellow and brown cardboard sign with unbroken portrait hinge at the back. Text on sign includes: Heel slippage is natural. It won't take long for your boots to break in. Sign carries the trademark of Acme Boot Company, a subsidiary of Northwest Industries.
  - 100-16-157. Acme Mineral Company, undated (Box 11)
    Copy reads: Feed Acme Minerals. Grow larger bone hogs, Put more strength in 'em. Supplies the mineral elements lacking in all feeds. Illustration shows a man holding the leg of a hog: Yes, Acme Minerals grows more bone. Poster is shrink wrapped with paper backing.
  - 100-16-158. Acme White Lead and Color Works, 1925 (Box 48B)
    Save the surface and you save all...Have an Acme Quality Shelf... Color images, black and white text. Torn along edges.
  - 100-16-159. Acme Steel Company, 1953 (Box 11)
    Acme Strapping Insures S. A. (Safe Arrival.). Black and white images and text. Dated in pen at bottom of poster.
  - 100-16-160. Acme Quality Paints Inc., 1950s (Box 11)
    Enjoy a more colorful life with Acme Modern Colors inside and outside your home! Color images and text. Very small tears along edges. Good condition.
  - 100-16-161. Acme Quality Paints Inc., 1924 (Box 48B)
    So easy when you use Acme Quality. Black and white images and text. Yellowing. Minor creasing.
  - 100-16-162. Acme Quality Paints Inc., 1920s (Box 11)
    For your very own! Here, of all places should be a reflection of your self... Color image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-163. Acme Quality Paints Inc., 1920s (Box 11)
    Houses, like folks, need new clothes... Color image and text. Water damage across lower left corner.
  - 100-16-164. Acme Markets, Inc., 1960 (Box 11)
    Garden goodness. Captured in cans by Acme... Color image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-165. Acme Boot Company, 1956 (Box 11)
    Make this an Acme Cowboy Boot Christmas... Color image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-166. Acme Boot Company, 1948 (Box 11)
    Acme Boots for back yard Buckaroos...Tested in the stirrup where it really counts. Color image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-167. Acme Visible Records Inc., 1945 (Box 11)
    Announcing the revolutionary new innovation in record keeping, Acme slidedex. The slide rule visible index... Black and white image and text. Good condition.
  - 100-16-168. Acme Quality Paints Inc., 1921 (Box 42)
    Soft warm walls transform your walls... Color image. Black and white text. God condition.
  - 100-16-169. Acme Card System Company, 1923 (Box 11)
    One Black-and-white advertisement from the American Magazine, p. 92, with handwritten date 1923. Text reads: He came to me with a plan;. advertisement has an illustration of a man holding the Acme Visible Equipment. Newsprint advertisement in good condition.
  - 100-16-170. Acme Markets, Inc. Newspaper insert, 1980s (Box 42)
    Newspaper insert flyer advertising Acme Frequent Buyer Cheks. Four-paged, colored flyer.
  - 100-16-171. Acme Players, 1997 (Box 11)
    Acme Players from Los Angeles, CA, Southern California's favorite comedy troupe. pose for a Head and Shoulders dandruff shampoo advertisement; advertisement appeared in Vibe magazine. Item in excellent condition.
  - 100-16-172. Acme Premium Supply Legalize Marijuana. poster, 1975 (Box 48E)
    One poster with a drawing of a marijuana leaf at the center and Legalize Marijuana. around it; a lighted joint. is shown below the sign. Small print on the poster reads: No. 108 c. Acme Premium Supply 1975. Poster is fragile, torn and taped in several places.
  - 100-16-173. Acme Boot Inc. Article on plant closure, undated (Box 42)
    One news clipping on the closure of Acme Boot Company in Waverly, Tenn, the sixth Acme plant to close since 1962. Newspaper source is unknown. The plant is the largest employer of the Waverly town of 4,400 people.
  - 100-16-174. Acme Boot Company. Acme Boots and Johnny Cash poster, undated (Box 48C)
    Color cardboard poster showing Johnny Cash and Acme Boots. Acme Boots not only look good they wear even better--Johnny Cash for Acme Boots on TV, Radio, and in National Magazines. Good condition.
  - 100-16-175. Acme Motor Truck Company. Magazine advertisement, 1920 (Box 11)
    One Black-and-white full paged advertisement from the October 9, 1920 issue of Literary Digest., p. 87. Copy reads: Acme Trucks at 90,000 miles. Advertisement shows image of the truck and the seal of dependable performance, Acme the Truck of proved units. Item in good condition.